Arts of China Lantern Slide Collection
Yale University Arts Library
Arts of China Lantern Slide Collection
1900-1960
VRC 3001
Yale University Arts Library
11
33 boxes
Collection consists of black and white glass lantern slides of Chinese arts of all periods, pre-historic to the mid-20th century. Includes architecture, painting, sculpture, calligraphy, ceramics, ivory, jade, lacquer, metalwork, textiles, rugs, and tapestry.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Scope and Contents
Collection consists of black and white glass lantern slides of Chinese arts of all periods, pre-historic to the mid-20th century. Includes architecture, painting, sculpture, calligraphy, ceramics, ivory, jade, lacquer, metalwork, textiles, rugs, and tapestry.
Arrangement
Arranged alphabetically by medium. Further sub-divided by location or chronological period, and if known, by individual artist name.
Arts -- China; Slides; Lantern slides; Reproductions
- Architecture (Box 1)
  - General (Box 1)
    - Various Titles (Box 1)
  - By Location (Box 1)
    - An-Ch'iu, Shantung (Box 1)
    - Anyang, Honan (Box 1)
    - Ch'angsha, Hunan (Box 1)
    - Chi-Nan, Shantung (Box 1)
    - Ch'ing-Tao, Shantung (Box 1)
    - Choni (Box 1)
    - Chu-Fu, Shantung (Box 1)
    - Chungking, Szechuan (Box 1)
    - Fu-Ch'ing, Fukien (Box 2)
    - Fu-Chou, Fukien (Box 2)
    - I-Nan, Shantung (Box 2)
    - Jehol, Szechuan (Box 2)
    - Jehol, Szechuan (Box 2)
    - Kuan-Hsien, Szechuan (Box 2)
    - Kuangchou, Kwantung (Box 2)
    - Kun-Ming, Yunnan (Box 2)
    - Lanchow, Kansu (Box 2)
    - Lo-Yang, Honan (Box 2)
    - Mai-T'ai-Ssu, Shensi (Box 2)
    - Miao-Ti-Kou (Box 2)
    - Nanking, Kiangsu (Box 2)
    - Nankow, Hopei (Box 2)
    - Pan-P'o (Box 2)
    - Peking (Box 2)
      - Various Titles (Box 2)
      - Maps & Plans (Box 3)
      - Chung-Ho-Tien (Box 3)
      - Fa-Hai Ssu (Box 3)
      - Forbidden City (Box 3)
      - Pagodas (Box 3)
      - Hopei (Box 3)
      - T'ai-Ho Tien (Box 4)
      - Temple of Heaven (Box 4)
      - Western Hills (Box 4)
      - Yuan-Ming Yuan (Box 4)
    - Pingyangfu, Shansi (Box 4)
    - Pingyangfu, Shansi (Box 4)
    - Shanghai, Kiangsu (Box 4)
    - Sian, Shensi (Box 4)
    - Soochou, Kiangsu (Box 4)
    - Ta-Li, Yunnan (Box 4)
    - Ta-T'ung, Shansi (Box 4)
    - T'ai-Shan Mountain, Shantung (Box 4)
    - T'ai-Yuan, Shansi (Box 4)
    - Teng-Feng, Honan (Box 4)
    - Tientsin, Hopei (Box 4)
    - Wu-Ch'ang, Hupeh (Box 5)
    - Wu-T'ai, Shansi (Box 5)
      - Various Titles (Box 5)
      - Fo-Kuang Ssu (Box 5)
    - Yen-An, Shansi (Box 5)
- Painting (Box 5)
  - General (Box 5)
    - Various Titles (Box 5)
    - Natural Scenery (Box 5)
  - Late Chou dynasty (Box 5)
  - Han dynasty (Box 5)
    - Various Titles (Box 5)
    - Spirit Robe, Ma-Wang-Tui (Box 5)
    - Noin-Ula (Box 5)
  - Six Dynasties (Box 5)
    - Various Titles (Box 5)
    - Ku K'ai-Chih (Box 5)
  - T'ang dynasty (Box 5)
    - Various Titles (Box 5)
    - Wan Fo Hsia Caves (Box 6)
    - Known Artists (Box 6)
      - Various Titles (Box 6)
      - Han Kan, ca. 710-760 (Box 6)
      - Li Cheng, ca. 800 (Box 6)
      - Li Ssu-Hsun, ca. 650-716 (Box 6)
      - P'ei K'uan (Box 6)
      - Wang Wei, 699-759 (Box 6)
      - Wei Ch'ih I-Seng, ac. 620-710 (Box 6)
      - Wu Tao-Tzu, 8th century (Box 6)
      - Yen Li-Pen, d. 673 (Box 6)
  - Five Dynasties (Box 6)
    - Various Titles (Box 6)
    - Known Artists (Box 6)
      - Chao Ch'ang (Box 6)
      - Ch'ing Hao, 900-960 (Box 6)
      - Ch'iu Wen-Po (Box 6)
      - Chou Wen-Chu, ac. 970 (Box 6)
      - Hsu-Hsi (Box 6)
      - Huang Ch'uan, d. 965 (Box 6)
      - Kuan-Hsiu, 906-960 (Box 7)
      - Ku Hung-Chung (Box 7)
      - Shih K'o, 10th century (Box 7)
      - Tung Yuan, late 10th century (Box 7)
  - Sung dynasty (Box 7)
    - Various Titles (Box 7)
    - Artist Unknown (Box 7)
      - Various Titles (Box 7)
      - Bird and Flower (Box 7)
      - Figures (Box 7)
      - Landscape (Box 7)
      - Lady Wen Chi's Return (Box 7)
      - Moore Album, YUAG (Box 7)
    - Known Artist (Box 8)
      - Chao Po-Chu, 12th century (Box 8)
      - Chao Pu-Chih (Box 8)
      - Chao Ta-Nien, ac. 1080-1100 (Box 8)
      - Ch'en Jung, ac. 1235-1250 (Box 8)
      - Chiang Shen (Box 8)
      - Ch'i Hsu (Box 8)
      - Chou Chi-Ch'ang, ac. c. 1163-1180 (Box 8)
      - Chu-Jan, ac. c. 975 (Box 8)
      - Fan K'uan, 990-1030 (Box 8)
      - Hsia Kuei, ac. c. 1180-1230 (Box 8)
        - Various Titles (Box 8)
        - 12 River ViewsHui Tsung, 1082-1135 (Box 8)
      - Hui Tsung, 1082-1135 (Box 8)
      - Li Ch'eng, 940-990 (Box 9)
      - Li Kung-Nien (Box 9)
      - Li Shan, ac. 1250 (Box 9)
      - Li T'ang, ac. c. 1100-1130 (Box 9)
      - Li Tzu-Ya, late 13th century (Box 9)
      - Liang K'ai (Box 9)
      - Lin T'ing-Kuei (Box 9)
      - Lu Hsin-Chung, 13th century (Box 9)
      - Ma Fen, ac. late 11th century (Box 9)
      - Ma Lin (Box 9)
      - Ma Yuan, ac. c. 1190-1224 (Box 9)
      - Mi Fei, 1051-1107 (Box 9)
      - Mi Yu-Jen, ac. c. 1120 (Box 9)
      - Mu-Ch'I, 13th century (Box 9)
      - Shih-Ke (Box 9)
      - Su Shih, 1036-1101 (Box 9)
      - Wang Hung, ac. 1150 (Box 9)
      - Wen T'ung, d. 1079 (Box 9)
      - Yen Tz'u-Ping, late 12th century (Box 9)
      - Yen Wen-Kuei, late 10th century (Box 9)
      - Yen-Yen, Lady (Box 9)
      - Ying-Yu-Chien, 13th century (Box 9)
  - Yuan dynasty (Box 9)
    - Various Titles (Box 9)
    - Artist Unknown (Box 9)
      - Various Titles (Box 9)
    - Known Artist (Box 9)
      - Chang Chung (Box 9)
      - Chang-Mu, b. 1289 (Box 9)
      - Chang Wo (Box 9)
      - Chao Meng-Fu, 1254-1322 (Box 9)
      - Chao Yung, c. 1289 (Box 10)
      - Ch'ien Hsuan, 1235-1290 (Box 10)
      - Fang Ts'ung-I (Box 10)
      - Huang Kung-Wang, 1269-1354 (Box 10)
      - Jen Jen-Fa (Box 10)
      - Kao Jan-Hui (Box 10)
      - Kao K'o-Kung, ac. c. 1275 (Box 10)
      - Kuan Tao-Sheng, 1262-1319 (Box 10)
      - Li-Kan (Box 10)
      - Li Yung-Chih (Box 10)
      - Ni Tsan, 1301-1374 (Box 10)
      - Sheng Mou, ac. mid 14th century (Box 10)
      - Tsao Chih-P'o, 14th century (Box 10)
      - Wang Chen-Peng, ac. 1312-1320 (Box 10)
      - Wang Meng, c. 1308-1385 (Box 10)
      - Wang Mien (Box 10)
      - Wang Yuan (Box 10)
      - Wu Chen, 1280-1354 (Box 11)
        - Various Titles (Box 11)
        - Bamboo (Box 11)
      - Yang Wei-Chen (Box 11)
      - Yen Hui, 14th century (Box 11)
  - Ming dynasty (Box 11)
    - Various Titles (Box 11)
    - Known Artist (Box 11)
      - Chang Chung (Box 11)
      - Chang Jui-T'u (Box 11)
      - Chang Lu, c. 1464-1538 (Box 11)
      - Ch'en Hung-Shou (Box 11)
      - Chen Ju-Yen, ac. 1340-1380 (Box 11)
      - Ch'en Shun, 1483-1544 (Box 11)
      - Cheng Wen-Lin (Box 11)
      - Ch'in-Ying, 16th century (Box 11)
      - Ch'iu Ying (Box 11)
      - Chou Wen-Ching, 1430-1460 (Box 11)
      - Fu Shan, 1605-1684 (Box 11)
      - Hsu Wei, 1521-1593 (Box 11)
      - Huang Tao-Chou, 1585-1646 (Box 12)
      - Jen Yueh-Shan, 14th century (Box 12)
      - Ku Cheng-I, c. 1580 (Box 12)
      - Kuo Chen (Box 12)
      - Li Shih-Ta (Box 12)
      - Liu Chueh, 1410-1472 (Box 12)
      - Mo Shih-Lung, ac. 1570 (Box 12)
      - Shang Hsi (Box 12)
      - Shao Mi, 17th century (Box 12)
      - Shen Chou, 1427-1509 (Box 12)
      - Shen Tu (Box 12)
      - Sheng Mao-Yeh (Box 12)
      - Tai Chin, mid 15th century (Box 12)
      - T'ang Yin, 1470-1523 (Box 12)
      - Ting Yuan-P'eng (Box 12)
      - Tung Ch'i-Chang (Box 12)
      - Wang E (Box 12)
      - Wang Fu (Box 12)
      - Wang Ku-Hsiang (Box 13)
      - Wang Shao-Ch'uan (Box 13)
      - Wang Shin (Box 13)
      - Wen Ch'eng-Ming (Box 13)
      - Wen Chia, 1500-1583 (Box 13)
      - Wen Fo-Jen, 1502-1575 (Box 13)
      - Wu Wei, 1459-1508 (Box 13)
  - Ching dynasty (Box 13)
    - Various Titles (Box 13)
    - Artist Unknown (Box 13)
      - Various Titles (Box 13)
    - Known Artist (Box 13)
      - Chang Feng, ac. 1645-1670 (Box 13)
      - Ch'en Lin (Box 13)
      - Fang Shih-Shu (Box 13)
      - Kao Ch'i-P'ei (Box 13)
      - K'un-Ts'an, ac. c. 1650-1675 (Box 13)
      - Lan Ying, ac. c. 1660 (Box 13)
      - Lang Shih-Ning, 1688-1766 (Box 13)
      - Lady Ma Chuan, ac. 1796 (Box 13)
      - Mao Hsiang, c. 1615-1692 (Box 13)
      - Pa-Ta Shan-Jen, ac. c.1634-1650 (Box 13)
      - Shih-Tao, 1660-1710 (Box 13)
        - Various Titles (Box 13)
        - Flower Album (Box 14)
        - Album Ching-Pin Tse (Box 14)
        - Landscapes (Box 14)
        - Landscape in Style of Ni Tsan (Box 14)
        - Stone Bridge in T'ien-T'ai-Shan (Box 14)
      - Tung Pang-Pa (Box 14)
      - Wang Chien (Box 14)
      - Wang Hui (Box 14)
      - Wang Liang-Chi'en (Box 14)
      - Wang Shih-Min, 1592-1680 (Box 14)
      - Wang Yuan-Ch'i, 1642-1715 (Box 14)
      - Wu Li (Box 14)
      - Yang Wen-Ts'ung, ac. 1668 (Box 14)
  - Republic (Box 14)
    - Various Titles (Box 14)
    - Known Artist (Box 14)
      - Chi Pai-Shih, 20th century (Box 14)
      - Feng Tzu-K'ai (Box 14)
      - Hsieh Chi-Liu (Box 15)
      - Hsu Pei-Hung (Box 15)
      - Lu Hung-Nien (Box 15)
      - Ssu-Tu Ch'iao (Box 15)
      - T'ang Yun (Box 15)
      - Tseng Yu-Ho (Box 15)
      - W'ang He-Nien, 20th century (Box 15)
      - Wang Ke-I (Box 15)
      - Yu Fei-An (Box 15)
- Sculpture (Box 15)
  - General (Box 15)
  - Shang dynasty (Box 15)
  - Chou dynasty (Box 15)
  - Han dynasty (Box 15)
    - Various Titles (Box 15)
    - Bronze (Box 15)
    - Ceramic (Box 15)
    - Iron (Box 16)
    - Stone (Box 16)
      - Various Titles (Box 16)
      - Tomb of Chen (Shen) (Box 16)
      - Chu Wei Stone (Box 16)
      - Tomb of Ho Ch'in Ping, Shensi (Box 16)
      - Tomb of Hsiao T'ang Shan (Box 16)
      - Tomb of Wu Liang-Tzu, Shantung (Box 16)
  - Six Dynasties (Box 16)
    - Various Titles (Box 16)
    - Bronze (Box 16)
      - Various Titles (Box 16)
      - Buddhas (Box 17)
    - Ceramic (Box 17)
    - Stone (Box 17)
      - Various Titles (Box 17)
      - Stele (Box 17)
      - Buddhas (Box 17)
      - Chimaera (Box 17)
      - Sarcophagi (Box 18)
      - Lung-Men Caves, Loyang, Honan (Box 18)
      - Hsiang T'ang Shan Caves, Hopei and Honan (Box 18)
      - Shih-K'u Ssu, Kung Hsien, Honan (Box 18)
      - T'ien Lung Shan Caves (Box 18)
      - Yun-Kang Caves, Ta-t'ung, Shansi (Box 18)
  - Sui dynasty (Box 18)
    - Various Titles (Box 18)
    - Bronze (Box 18)
    - Ceramic (Box 18)
    - Stone (Box 18)
  - T'ang dynasty (Box 18)
    - Bronze (Box 18)
    - Ceramic (Box 18)
      - Various Titles (Box 18)
      - Animals (Box 18)
      - Tomb Figurines (Box 18)
    - Dry Lacquer (Box 19)
    - Stone (Box 19)
      - Various Titles (Box 19)
      - Stele (Box 19)
      - Chien-Hsi K'ou, Lang-chuang, Szechuan (Box 19)
      - Hua-T'a Ssu, Hsian, Shenshi (Box 19)
      - Lung Men Caves, Lo-yang, Honan (Box 19)
      - Ta-Yen T'a, Hsi-An, Shensi (Box 19)
      - T'ien Lung Shan Caves (Box 19)
      - Ts'ien-Fo Ya, Chia-chiang, Szechuan (Box 19)
      - Wu-Yiu Ssu, Lo-shan, Szechuan (Box 19)
    - Wood (Box 19)
  - Five Dynasties (Box 20)
    - Various Titles (Box 20)
  - Liao dynasty (Box 20)
    - Various Titles (Box 20)
  - Sung dynasty (Box 20)
    - Various Titles (Box 20)
    - Bronze (Box 20)
    - Ceramic (Box 20)
    - Iron (Box 20)
    - Stone (Box 20)
    - Wood (Box 20)
  - Yuan dynasty (Box 20)
    - Wood (Box 20)
  - Ming dynasty (Box 20)
    - Ceramic (Box 20)
    - Stone (Box 20)
      - Various Titles (Box 20)
      - Ming Tombs, Ch'ang-ping, Hopei (Box 20)
        - Various Titles (Box 20)
        - Civil Attendants & Warriors (Box 20)
    - Wood (Box 21)
  - Ch'ing dynasty (Box 21)
    - Bronze (Box 21)
- Calligraphy (Box 21)
  - Various Titles (Box 21)
  - Six Dynasties (Box 21)
  - T'ang dynasty (Box 21)
  - Sung dynasty (Box 21)
  - Yuan dynasty (Box 21)
  - Ming dynasty (Box 21)
- Ceramics (Box 21)
  - Prehistoric (Box 21)
    - Various Titles (Box 21)
    - Kansu (Box 21)
    - Manchuria (Box 22)
    - Shansi (Box 22)
  - Shang dynasty (Box 22)
    - Various Titles (Box 22)
  - Yin – Chou dynasty (Box 22)
    - Various Titles (Box 22)
    - Late Chou (Box 22)
    - East Chou (Box 22)
  - Han dynasty (Box 22)
  - Six Dynasties (Box 22)
  - T'ang dynasty (Box 22)
  - Sung dynasty (Box 22)
  - Yuan dynasty (Box 23)
  - Ming dynasty (Box 23)
  - Ch'ing dynasty (Box 23)
- Ivory (Box 23)
  - Various Titles (Box 23)
  - Shang dynasty (Box 23)
  - Yin – Chou dynasty (Box 23)
    - Early Chou (Box 24)
    - Middle Chou (Box 24)
    - Late Chou (Box 24)
  - Han dynasty (Box 24)
  - Sung dynasty (Box 24)
  - Ming dynasty (Box 24)
  - Ch'ing dynasty (Box 24)
- Lacquer (Box 24)
  - Various Titles (Box 24)
- Metal (Box 24)
  - General (Box 24)
  - Shang dynasty (Box 24)
    - Various Titles (Box 24)
    - Axes (Box 25)
    - Chia (Box 25)
    - Chih (Box 25)
    - Ho (Box 25)
    - Hu (Box 25)
    - I (Box 25)
    - Ku (Box 25)
    - Kuang (Box 25)
    - Kuei (Box 26)
    - Lei (Box 26)
    - Li (Box 26)
    - Ting (Box 26)
    - Yu (Box 26)
  - Yin Chou dynasty (Box 26)
    - Various Titles (Box 26)
      - Ho (Box 26)
      - Kuang (Box 26)
      - Owl Vase (Box 26)
      - Ting (Box 26)
    - Early Chou (Box 27)
      - Various Titles (Box 27)
      - Bell (Box 27)
      - Chia (Box 27)
      - Fang I (Box 27)
      - Hu (Box 27)
      - Kuang (Box 27)
      - Kuei (Box 27)
      - Lei (Box 27)
      - Ting (Box 27)
      - Tsun (Box 27)
      - Yu (Box 27)
    - Middle Chou (Box 28)
      - Various Titles (Box 28)
      - Hu (Box 28)
      - Kuei (Box 28)
      - Tiger (Box 28)
      - Yu (Box 28)
    - Late Chou (Box 28)
      - Various Titles (Box 28)
      - Bell (Box 28)
      - Chien (Box 28)
      - Hu (Box 28)
      - Mirror (Box 28)
      - Ting (Box 29)
      - Tou (Box 29)
      - Tui (Box 29)
  - Han dynasty (Box 29)
    - Various Titles (Box 29)
    - Ordos Bronzes (Box 29)
    - Mirrors (Box 29)
  - Six Dynasties (Box 29)
  - T'ang dynasty (Box 29)
  - Sung dynasty (Box 29)
- Textiles (Box 30)
  - Various Titles (Box 30)
  - Han (Box 30)
  - T'ang (Box 30)
  - Ming (Box 30)
  - Ch'ing (Box 30)
- Rugs (Box 30)
  - Various Titles (Box 30)
- "China Dups" (Box 31–33)
  General
  164 painting lantern slides reviewed by Richard Bamhart. Set aside as duplicates.